### **OBJECTIVE**

I want to deliver a strong message, through making real changes aimed towards improving and making the place we live in better. A place that allows people to have an obstacle-free path that allows unlimited growth. Therefore, I will dedicate my passion and ambition for problem-solving, analytical skills, and my various and extremely competent Software Engineering expertise in multiple fields to achieve this goal.

### **EDUCATION**

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals (KFUPM)

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia Sep 2016 - May 2021 ~5 years

Georgia Institute of Technology (GT)

Exchange Program, Computer Science

Atlanta, GA, United States Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

~5 months

## **EXPERIENCE**

Saudi Federation for Cyber Security and Programming

Lead Instructor

iOS Session Lead

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Sep 2021 - Present ~5 months

Axenda Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Founder & Leader

• Working with a team of 2-90 people, lead/manage when needed.

o Working on products' structure, design, and implementation.

Dhanran, Saudi Arabia

Mar 2020 - Present ~1 year, 8 months

Mohtwize Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Software Engineer

Output

Working on various projects as an architect and as a developer

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 ~2 months

Sary Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Product Intern / Business Analyst

o Analyzing product processes for optimization while

also identifying problems for solutions

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020 ~5 months

Udacity Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Explaining iOS nanodegree concepts through weekly meeting with students

o Setting up a Slack channel and frequently communicating with students on Slack

Mar 2019 - Aug 2020 ~1 year, 6 months

TechBench

Member / Technical Lead

Oct 2018 - Aug 2020

o Introducing tech to people by conducting workshops, and hackathons

o Leading the development of Enigma and other projects

Oct 2018 - Aug 2020 ~1 year, 10 months

### King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals (KFUPM)

Intro to Computing Grader

o Advanced my skills in OOP programming, specifically, with Java

o Wrote JavaScript scripts to automate some of the grading tasks

**Database Systems Grader** 

o Assisting course professor & grading assignments

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

~3 months

Feb 2020 - May 2020 ~4 months

Tweetso Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

iOS DeveloperDeveloped two native iOS applications (Experto, and Experto Provider)

o Worked with Firebase services such as Authentication and Databases

Nov 2017 - Jul 2018

~9 months

# PROJECTS (for more click here)

El Jabal (Swift, Firebase, Python, and JavaScript)

• An iOS application that serves students at KFUPM (Not official)

- Helps students to make a full graduation plan
- Gives the ability to browse KFUPM's course offerings

Enigma (Nginx, PM2, Node.js, Vue.js, and PostgreSQL)

Feb 2019 - Mar 2019

Mar 2018 - Mar 2020

- o A programming contest control system
- Used in TechBench's HackDay which was sponsored by Saudi Aramco and Information & Computer Science department at KFUPM
- Lots of teamwork

### **AWARDS**

### Wa'ed Hackathon at Dhahran Techno Valley (DTV) and Ithra

First Place, Recreational Activities Challenge

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Dec 2018

# SAP Hackathon at King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST)

Top Three, Smart Parking Challenge

Thuwal, Saudi Arabia

Feb 2019

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

### Udacity

Front End Web Developer Nanodegree Apr 2019
Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree Dec 2018
iOS Developer Nanodegree Nov 2018

# **VOLUNTEERISM**

## **KFUPM Voluntary Work Unit**

Volunteer Assistant

- Participated in the annual volunteering day at KFUPM for three years
- Worked with people from different backgrounds

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia Feb 2018, 2019, 2020 Microsoft Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
Trainer Dec 2017

Worked together along with Microsoft engineers

Introduced Microsoft's micro-computer 'micro:bit' to children on a workshop

Code.orgDhahran, Saudi ArabiaTrainerDec 2017

- Worked together along with 12 other volunteers from KFUPM
- Introduced Code.org to 402 children throughout several workshops

## **REFERENCES**

**Database Systems Assistant Professor, KFUPM** Salah Adam

adam@kfupm.edu.sa

**Learning Experience Design Manager, Udacity** Dania Abedaljawad

dania.abedaljawad@udacity.com